Pietro Torrico Escobar, Front End Developer

+591 69531998, torricopietro@gmail.com

LINKS	LinkedIn, GitHub, Portafolio	
PROFILE	Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience working with React, Next.js, Nodejs, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to deliver exceptional user experiences. Expert in contributing to highly collaborative work environments, findingsolutions, and ensuring customer satisfaction.	
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY		
Agu 2021 — Present	Front End Developer, Loop Corporation	Cochabamba, Bolivia
	Who gives a crap [USA]	
	 Optimized the checkout page by automatically autofilling fields through API connections, reducing the dropout rate by 7%. Developed the client admin panel, migrating from a React SPA to a Next.js application, improving performance through server-side rendering. Created a new shopping cart, reducing cart abandonment by improving UX and implementing a pop-up system. 	
	Tech Stack:	
	React, Liquid, Shopify, Typescript, Styled Components, Apollo graphql, Redux, Nextjs, Webpack	
	Acceso 360 [Spain]	
	 Developed an integrated system for management, collection, and automated content delivery and news by creating a SPA with React using Domain Driven Design, used by over 300 marketing agencies, news agencies, content agencies, and governments. Optimized the creation of advanced search for news collection, improving quality and match of collected news by implementing Lucene syntax validation. Developed the design system using React, Tailwind, StoryBook, and Vitest, increasing development team productivity through reusable components. Implemented unit tests using Vitest, doubling the number of unit tests in the application, reducing bugs and improving code quality. 	
	Tech Stack:	
	React, Tailwind, Zustand, Tankstackquery, Typescript, Docker, API Rest, Vitest ,DDD	
Aug 2023 — Feb 2024	Front end Developer, Alhasoft (Freelancer)	La Paz, Bolivia
	 Developed a real estate investment platform with Next.js, leveraging its server-side rendering capabilities for SEO optimization, successfully raising over \$10,000 on the first day of launch. Integrated a payment gateway, allowing users to utilize more than 5 payment methods by connecting to the "PagosNet" API. Implemented user validation and restriction through an authentication system, account validation, and password recovery. Utilized Web3 to interact with the blockchain and generate smart contracts. 	
	Tech Stack:	
	React, NextJs, Tailwind, Redux, Typescript, API Rest	
EDUCATION		
Jan 2018 — Dec 2021	Technical Superior in Computer Systems, ICEPAL Technical Institute	Cochabamb
IDIOMAS	Navite Spanish Fig. 1.1. P2	

• English B2